<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD Simplified DocBook XML V1.1//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/simple/1.1/sdocbook.dtd">
<article>
  <title>Content Math</title>

  <section>
    <title>Content Math</title>

    <para>Content Math support is based on an XSLT transformation script.
    Although this script is now integrated into JEuclid, it has its own
    homepage at:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink
        url="http://www.lri.fr/~pietriga/mathmlc2p/mathmlc2p.html">MathMLc2p
        Homepage</ulink></para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><ulink
        url="http://sourceforge.net/tracker/?group_id=44862&amp;atid=1042625">MathMLc2p
        Tracker</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>At this point the content math support is to be considered
    preliminary. Therefore feature wishes and bug fixes are greatly
    appreciated!</para>

    <para>Please note that content math <emphasis>only works if your document
    is in the MathML namespace</emphasis>. Declaring the DTD is not
    sufficient!</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Hacking Content Math</title>

    <para>Content MathML depends on an <ulink
    url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/XSL_Transformations">XSL
    Transformation</ulink> Script which transforms content MathML into
    presentation MathML. You can download the current version from the <ulink
    url="./source-repository.html">JEuclid Source repository</ulink>.
    Alternatively, you may try the following link:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink
        url="http://jeuclid.hg.sourceforge.net/hgweb/jeuclid/jeuclid/raw-file/tip/jeuclid-core/src/main/resources/net/sourceforge/jeuclid/content/mathmlc2p.xsl">Content
        Math To Presentation Math XSLT Script</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>Once you have the script, please use it to manually transform your
    content MathML to presentation MathML. You can use
    <command>xsltproc</command> on Unix/Linux systems, or <ulink
    url="http://xml.apache.org/xalan-j/">Apache Xalan</ulink> on all Java
    platforms.</para>

    <para>Make your modifications, test them manually, and submit a patch to
    the Content Math Tracker (see link above). Please Note: <emphasis>In many
    cases, the exact representation of content MathML is subjective. If your
    modifications are something you "prefer", then please a parameter for it!
    If it is something that you are sure everyone wants (because it is missing
    or breaks semantics), feel free to just patch the affected
    area.</emphasis></para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Passing parameters to the transformation</title>

    <para>Is still unsupported, due to the lack of a good idea on how to
    support it. It will likely be similar to the standard <ulink
    url="./extensions.html">JEuclid extensions</ulink>.</para>
  </section>
</article>
