<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD Simplified DocBook XML V1.1//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/simple/1.1/sdocbook.dtd">
<article>
  <title></title>

  <section id="about">
    <title>About JEuclid</title>

    <para>JEuclid is a complete MathML rendering solution, consisting
    of:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>A MathViewer application</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Command line converters from MathML to other formats</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>An ant task for automated conversion</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Display components for AWT and Swing</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>A component for Apache Cocoon</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Development version</title>

    <para>This page is generated from the stable, 3.0 branch of JEuclid.
    Please see the <ulink url="./trunk/">JEuclid development (trunk)
    webpage</ulink> for up-to-date information on the new development
    branch.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>News</title>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>JEuclid 3.0.2 Released.</para>

        <para>This release fixes some minor bug discoverd since 3.0.1. It is recommended for all users.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>JEuclid 3.0.1 Released.</para>

        <para>With the bug reports flowing in after the stable release, a
        maintenance release was in order.</para>

        <para>This release also contains the MathML plugin for the upcoming
        fop 0.94 version. Please note that JEuclid requires JDK 1.5 or
        higher.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>JEuclid 3.0.0 Released!</para>

        <para>JEuclid is a complete MathML rendering solution. After being
        dormant for a while, the project has picked up development again and
        we are now able to provide a new major release.</para>

        <para>JEuclid 3.0 consists of:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>A MathML viewer application</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Command line converters from MathML to other image formats,
            including JPEG, BMP, WBMP, GIF, SVG, EMF, PDF, PS, SWF</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>An ant task for automated conversion</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Java display components for AWT and Swing</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>A FO preprocessor application to support MathML in xsl-fo
            renderers</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>Two plugins are part of JEuclid:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>A XXE Plugin provides MathML support for <ulink
            url="http://www.xmlmind.com/">XMLMind XML-Editor</ulink> and is
            available through the XXE update site</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>A FOP plugin provides MathML support in <ulink
            url="http://xmlgraphics.apache.org/fop/">FOP</ulink>. It will be
            released shortly after the fop 0.94 release.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>For more information, please see ask at
        jeuclid-users@liss.sourceforge.net .</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Announcing JEuclid 2.9.8 aka 3.0 RC: We're almost there: The new
        Release is just around the corner!</para>

        <para>There have been few bugfixes to the core module, but most of the
        work has been gone into the support:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>FOP support is actively being worked on with patches
            submitted to FOP to allow for better integration.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>a <ulink url="http://www.xmlmind.com/xmleditor/">XXE</ulink>
            plugin adds support for MathML in XXE.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>a new FOPREP application can now be used to prepare XSL-FO
            files by replacing all instream MathML with SVG codes and adding
            the correct baseline-shift, to allow proper rendering of MathML in
            XSL-FO applications wihout MathML support.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>JEuclid 2.9.7 (3.0b2) released</para>

        <para>In the spirit of getting closer to 3.0, the JEuclid team is
        proud to announce the release of JEuclid 2.9.7, aka 3.0beta2. As
        promised, the external API is fully compatible with 2.9.6, and will
        stay stable until the 3.0 release.</para>

        <para>Some of the most notable changes:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>compatibility improvements in Swing component: It behaves
            more like a "standard" swing component.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>split up into smaller modules to allow better selection of
            required components.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>batik for SVG support is now optional.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Two distributions: a "minimal" distribution (approx. 600k)
            without extra image converters, and a "complete" distribution
            (approx. 3300k) with extra image converters</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>support for new output formats: EMF, GIF, PDF, PS, SWF
            through the help of FreeHEP</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>an updated plug-in for fop 0.93</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>numerous bugfixes which improve stability and rendering
            quality.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>JEuclid 2.9.6 is released</para>

        <para>This release has had a lot of refactoring. Many elements have
        moved and been renamed. All internal coordinates have been changed to
        use "float" instead of int. Please update your code
        accordingly.</para>

        <para>The good news is that the refactoring is done, and therefore the
        API WILL REMAIN STABLE until 3.0. No existing public functionality
        will be removed! There may be some deprecations before 3.0, but this
        is not anticipated! It is now time to update JEuclid referencing
        projects, such as the FOP-Plugin.</para>

        <para>It is also noteworthy that this release of JEuclid supports ALL
        MATHML 2.0 PRESENTATION ELEMENTS. Any valid MathML 2.0 presentation
        can therefore be rendered with. Some lesser used attributes are still
        missing, but they do not hinder rendering.</para>

        <para>Also noteworthy is that this release features and FULLY
        MODIFIABLE INTERNAL TREE, based on the standard W3C DOM
        mapping.</para>

        <para>And last, but not least FULL SUPPORT FOR ALL OPENOFFICE FOMULAR
        (.ODF) files.</para>

        <para>With all these features, this is now BETA-1 for JEuclid 3.0;
        Please file bug reports, and send your wishes to the jeuclid-* mailing
        list, so that I can release 3.0 soon!</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>JEuclid 2.9.5 is released</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Don't want to download? Try our new <ulink
        url="./webstart.html">Webstartable MathViewer
        application</ulink>.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>JEuclid 2.9.4 is released</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>We now have a <ulink url="./logo.html">Logo</ulink></para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>The sourcecode repository has moved to subversion, please see
        <ulink url="./source-repository.html">Source repository</ulink> for
        updated instructions.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>The project is now built with and maintained by <ulink
        url="http://maven.apache.org">Maven</ulink>!</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>Please <ulink url="./issue-tracking.html">report any
    issues</ulink>.</para>
  </section>
</article>
